Come on
Dammit.
Come on, you gotta
be kidding me.
I'm surprised it
lasted that long.
You know, you'd think
that a bunch of Mormons
who got together in their
little covered wagons
and made it all the way out west
to build their city on
top of a patch of salt,
that maybe, just maybe,
they'd build a radio tower.
But no, not the Mormons.
Well,
we're in Miller County.
What's that mean?
It means there's not
so much as a gas station
between here and Nevada.
You should have brought a book.
Think
they'd spring for us
to be put up in Salt Lake
City for one night, huh?
One night.
Salt Lake City?
- Yeah.
- What would you have done
in Salt Lake City?
Tipped cows?
You kidding me?
All those Mormon
girls with no booze,
no dancing, no culture,
just fighting over some frozen
- peckerwood preacher.
- Hey,
look sharp.
Is that our man?
Looks nothing like him.
Howdy.
Dang thing blew a gasket.
I don't think I can fix it.
I don't think you can.
Ain't no water out here,
and Sulphurdale's
ten mile that way.
I'd be obliged if
you help me out.
Help with what?
You got a spare
gasket back there?
Well, I reckon, I don't
know for sure it's the gasket.
I've been working on it all day.
It's all busted up.
This old jalopy's got
a ton of miles on her.
I'm lucky you came
along while you did.
Ain't nothing out here
but critters and
Mormons farming oats.
Ambush!
Don't move.
Drop your guns or I shoot.
Both of you.
You move, I shoot him.
Okay.
Don't shoot.
I got 'em.
Crash, I got 'em.
Yeah.
He got 'em.
Pilgrims!
I am Crash Mooncalf with
the Crash Mooncalf Gang.
And I run this here
part of this here state.
And you passing through my
part of this here state,
means you owe me debt.
Jimmy!
Collect my debt, huh?
Mr. Mooncalf says
you owe debt, city boy.
I have no money.
He says he ain't got no money.
Bullshit!
That's a brand new car.
Those are brand new
fancy-pants suits, huh?
Fancy-pants suits.
If you don't put
your limp-wristed
hands high in the air
and step out with your
billfolds spilling cash money,
I'm gonna air you fuckers out.
Hey, we don't
want any trouble.
We'll give you our money, okay?
Tommy.
My billfold's in my pocket.
I'm gonna grab it slow.
Don't shoot.
All right?
Here we go.
I got 600
right here.
Okay?
I got 600 right here.
My partner's got
a thousand.
Take the money, you let us go.
No!
Get 'em.
Hey!
Hold your fire!
You down there!
It's just the two of you.
Now, drop your guns.
Can't do that, Mr. Mooncalf!
My name is Frank Fenton.
My partner and I
are U.S. Marshals.
I have a warrant for your arrest
signed by a federal
magistrate judge
in Ormsby County, Nevada.
That means drop
your guns, dumbass!
Nothing doing, Marshal.
I got a bead on
your man in the car.
You drop your guns.
He ain't got a
bead on shit, Frank.
There's no need to spill
any more blood today,
Mr. Mooncalf.
Let's negotiate.
Negotiate?
I can talk him down.
Mr. Mooncalf, use your head.
You got two marshals right here
and a hundred on your
tail if we go down.
There's only one way this ends.
I'm a crack shot.
We're both crack shots.
You best back off.
You best back off!
We can take them, Frank.
There's only one
way, Mr. Mooncalf.
You know that.
Come on!
Damn you, Marshal!
Damn it, Tommy!
Cover me!
Hot damn, Frank.
I got that sucker
dead to rights.
You see that?
What in the hell was that?
What?
Don't put your hands on me.
Our job is serving warrants
and bringing in fugitives alive.
You know that!
For God's sake, we had him.
He would have surrendered.
He wasn't gonna surrender.
I did the job so
you didn't have to.
You're welcome.
Don't you walk away from me.
Don't you touch me!
You negotiate first.
Then shoot.
You do not go in guns
blazing every time!
That gang killed
families, Frank.
We stopped the bad guys.
That's the job.
Tommy,
this isn't a cowboy movie.
Yeah, well, sometimes
a cowboy's what you need.
I'm gonna call it in.
Fillin' her up?
Just topping off.
You here for the sheriff?
Only reason anybody in a
suit's gonna be in Gilead
is to drive down to the
county seat in Fort Tipton
and see the sheriff.
Is that so?
Well, ever since the murders.
The sheriff ain't in his office.
Where is he?
He's up off the
State Line Road
at the McCluskey homestead.
What's left of it.
Well, I guess
that's where we're headed.
Yep, well,
they was murdered.
The McCluskeys.
All of 'em.
You need anything for the road?
I'll take a 7-UP.
Got anything a
little stronger?
Hey, you want one?
No, thanks.
Suit yourself.
We got the federal warrant
served before lunch.
What do you think the odds
are we can make it a twofer
and get this rinky dink state
warrant served before supper?
I wouldn't hold my breath.
This one might get complicated.
Sheriff.
What?
I'm Frank Fenton.
This is my partner, Tom.
We're U.S. Marshals.
Marshals?
Where's the coroner?
Paiute
County has no coroner.
They got me and my deputy.
Yeah, middle of
nowhere here, huh?
I live here.
This is Paiute country.
Only flat dicks in DC think
this is the middle of nowhere.
Now pick that up.
And, uh, feel free
to look around.
Best we can tell is that
the perps entered here.
And whoever kicked the
door in was not invited.
Any idea who did this?
Yeah, Benjamin Bonney.
You here to serve him a warrant?
Yeah, we're here
to serve his warrant.
You sure it was him?
Dead positive.
Anybody who lives within
a mile of his ranch,
he shoots them in the head and
just burns down their house.
And not a
single speck of evidence?
That's right.
He's real good.
Not one speck of
evidence until last week.
We found a casing
that's matched his iron.
How far away is his ranch?
Uh...
See that other side
of that mountain?
He lives up there with
these three half-wit sons.
Three sons?
Yeah, Noah, Ahab, and Joe.
Now I've never really seen Joe,
but I've heard a lot about him.
Every crime scene always
had four sets of footprints.
So they're all involved.
Son of a bitch.
Three kids.
Dossier said two, right?
"Benjamin Bonney,
born 8/18/1902, Gilead,"
uh, blah blah.
"Married in 1924.
Produced two offspring,
two sons, Ahab and Noah."
Two.
So who's this Joe kid, huh?
Some illegitimate half-breed?
Look, the warrant is
for Benjamin Bonney.
We just gotta bring in one guy.
We play it smart.
We feel it out.
Well, you better find
us a motel with a bar.
Hey, pigtails.
Can I get another tequila?
Actually, make it two.
Two more coming up.
So there's
something I don't get.
What don't you get, Tommy?
Why us?
Why'd they send a
couple of marshals
to this little podunk hickville
to serve a county warrant?
I mean, I get the
sheriff's outgunned.
Look at that guy.
He could barely stand.
But why did the
FBI kick it down?
Well, I'm sure our
friends at the FBI
didn't want to deal with
a couple of dead miners
in Indian country.
So we got sent on a milk
run after the Mooncalf grab.
Seems pretty cut
and dried to me.
I just don't get why
the FBI passed on it.
Here you go, boys.
Much obliged.
Now what is your name?
Name's Callie.
You here about the murders?
Ooh, cat's out of the
bag, Frank.
Shot?
No, thank you.
You think it's land
they're after, the Bonneys?
Well,
hell.
Anyone with any sense knows so.
Is that right?
Them boys got a grudge and
they'll spill blood over it.
Ben Bonney's daddy
owned 10,000 acres
of God's country around here.
Largest ranch in the mine area.
When he went off and
got killed by the Indians,
the bank took it,
sold it off in plots,
and I bought one of them plots.
You see, there ain't nobody
got no recollection of it
except Ben Bonney
and a few others.
A man thinks something's
rightfully his
and it gets took from
him's a dangerous man.
Ben Bonney's even worse.
So he's trying to buy back
the land at bottom dollar?
Hell, he low-balled me
to the tune of $20 an acre.
Turned him down.
Next week, had two dead
horses shot through the head.
He come back the next day,
offered me $10 an acre.
Did you take it?
Nope.
I like this guy.
I always figured
my end would be the
bottom of a mine shaft,
inflation would run me off,
or Soviet Reds would get me.
I never ever dreamed
it'd be the cloven-hoofed
devil himself.
Ma'am.
How about that?
We get to arrest the
cloven-hoofed devil himself.
The whole country's gone to
half to hell if you ask me.
Mama'd spin in her grave.
If it's not murderers,
it's the communists.
Didn't used to be like this.
It won't always be like this.
That's how you flirt?
Mind your business. Tommy.
So this
Benjamin Bonney guy, right?
He's out there, what?
Killing landowners and
then buying up the plots?
And he thinks he's not
gonna get caught.
- What?
Oh, come on, Tommy.
Shh.
Hi, boys.
Hello, yourself.
What's your name?
Dinah.
What's yours?
Tommy.
You want a drink?
Sure.
Don't mind if I do
Hot damn, Dinah.
Where are you from?
Twin Falls, Idaho.
- Idaho?
- Mm-hmm.
What-what are you doing
all the way down here?
Oh, just looking
for a boyfriend.
It might be you if you
play your cards right.
Miss, we're U.S. Marshals.
Is that a crime?
No.
Just keep it above
board, please.
Mm.
My son likes those.
He's four.
So, you got a girlfriend?
Well, I
think I might now.
Mm.
You staying here?
I am.
Just outside.
Uh, Tommy, we're marshals.
Yeah, you said that already.
Frank.
You think I'm a prostitute?
You think I'm trying
to take his money?
Well, I'm not.
I'm not for sale.
I just...
I like Tommy.
And you're gonna give
me some gas money
to get back home to my
little boy next week?
Well, that only sounds fair.
$20?
Hey, Frank, can I borrow $10?
I'm kidding.
All right.
That sounds fair to me.
Frank, don't you
wait up.
How's it going, darling?
Look at that dress.
I love the way it moves.
- Take it off.
- I cannot wait
to see what it looks like
on the floor.
Left you with the bill, huh?
I'll collect on it.
Smoke?
No, thank you.
I gave them up 10 years ago.
You really a marshal?
I am.
And you're really
going after the Bonneys?
Looks that way.
Drinks on the house.
Whole valley's scared
to go near them.
Oh.
Well, thank you, Callie.
They're dangerous.
Next time you might need
something a little stronger.
All right.
I got six shots in my pistol,
and every one of them's
got your name on it.
Well, well, well, if
it ain't Durango Jack.
Last I heard you were lightin'
out for Indian territory.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, here you go.
- Yeah, right there.
Here you go, here you go.
All right.
Confound
you, Durango Jack!
Lo and behold, church
on wheels.
Quite a sight, isn't it?
Yeah.
What, are you some
kind of preacher?
That I am.
Reverend Cassidy
Whitaker at your service.
My friends call me Cass.
Frank.
How do you do Frank?
I've never seen a
traveling church before.
You mean you've never seen
a man roam from town to town,
in a preacher wagon, bothering
strange men in parking lots?
You gotta get out more, Frank.
You starting a revival?
There's already a revival.
I'm just bringing
it to Paiute County.
Hm.
First altar call
tomorrow night.
Free Bible if you want it.
Oh.
Yeah, the Gideons
beat you to that one.
You got me there.
Of course, the Gideons
can't give you more
than what fits in a drawer.
But Frank,
this place
is special.
I can feel it.
A man in your line of
work might benefit.
What kind of work is that?
Well, you're a man
of the law, aren't you?
How'd you guess?
Turn around
- What?
- Turn around.
I'm unarmed.
Shh.
Shoulders of a law man.
A thousand burdens in
every fiber of muscle.
You're still holding it tight.
What are you,
some kind of shrink?
Just a man of the Lord, Frank.
But you don't need to have
religion to call me a friend.
I've been down some hard roads.
You ever need an ear or
a hand or anything else,
I'm your man.
Thank you.
I'm an Evangelist, baby.
Good will don't cost me a thing.
I'm gonna catch some shut
eye in the preacher wagon.
You have yourself a good night.
Hey, you too.
Thank you.
7AM.
Oh, shit, I gotta go.
No.
- Where's my wallet?
- Right now?
Rise and shine, kiddo.
I gotta
go, I gotta go.
I gotta go.
Hey.
Be safe, baby doll.
I'll see you tonight.
Yeah.
Mm.
Don't get shot.
Is that coffee?
Oh, man.
Is she staying?
Yeah.
She needed gas
money and then, uh,
turns out her engine
needed an overhaul,
so I had to work
on that all night.
Jesus.
All right, Casanova, it's
time to clock in.
What the hell?
I need a bullet.
Grab a canteen.
Shoot me.
I need a bullet.
Hang on, pal, we're
getting you water.
Shoot me.
Sh-sh-shoot...
Sh-sh-sh-shoot me.
Shoot me.
What did you do?
I put him out of his misery.
You heard him.
Poor bastard was begging for it.
Frank,
are you all right?
Yes.
Yeah, I'm all right.
I'm all right.
I get like that too sometimes.
Call it in.
That's Don Burgess.
At least he had the common
courtesy to shoot him.
I shot him.
I think you did
the right thing.
Poor bastard.
That's one hell of a way to go.
Sheriff,
the whole place is done for.
Shack's burnt down and
the horses shot dead.
Same as the McCluskey place.
We met him last night in town.
- Hm.
- He gave us reason to believe
Bonney has some sort of
ties to the land here.
Yeah, I heard that.
And?
Can't you check?
Don't you have a
courthouse here?
We keep our archives
in the basement of the
courthouse in Fort Tipton.
But it mysteriously burnt down
two weeks before
these murders started.
Huh.
Covering his tracks.
Well,
we'll have him at the
business end of a gun soon.
I'm telling you, they
are very dangerous men,
so you and Barney Fife
here better watch your ass.
All right there.
Big ol' fancy ranch with
no cattle and no horses.
And they got a storage barn,
but they aren't growing crops.
Get out!
Hey, we're unarmed!
Stop shooting!
State
your business!
We're Mormon!
Mormons?
That doesn't help your case any.
Hey, stop it!
I'm offering you diplomacy here.
Beg your pardon,
Mormon, but I'm no diplomat.
What we gonna do here, Frank?
What are we gonna do, Frank?
Sir, what are we gonna do?
What are we gonna do?
Tommy,
cover me!
Shit!
Tommy, get over here!
Drop your guns or
I throw grenades
through every window
of this house!
Congratulations.
You're the first pair of Mormons
to ever shoot their way
through the front door.
Are you Benjamin Bonney?
I am not.
I'm Mickey Mouse.
And these are my
associates, Jim and Judy.
Hi.
Nice to meet you.
You come to plug holes
in the front of my house?
Tell you what, why don't
you join us for dinner?
You.
What's your name?
Ahab.
And you?
Noah?
That's right
Where is Joe?
I'm beginning to suspect that
you're not actually Mormons.
No, no, wait.
Give me a minute.
Don't tell me.
You're U.S. Marshals
and you're here 'cause
you got something to say.
Yeah, we do.
We have a warrant
for your arrest
on the charge of capital murder.
Capital murder?
Oh, good heavens.
I'd better comply.
Gentlemen, here are my wrists.
Just slap the irons on me and
drag me off to the hangman.
That is exactly what
we're going to do.
You will have your day in
court if you come peacefully.
Oh, did you hear that?
I'm going to get
my day in court.
Yeah.
Uh, you know, uh, if you please,
Marshals, I was wondering
if I can have a look at
a copy of that warrant.
That'd help me come
along peacefully.
Yeah.
Issued by a
Paiute County judge.
Hm.
Well, now, you must be mistaken.
Um, it says here it's
issued on November 13th
and that was, uh,
well over a week ago.
That's right.
Warrants don't expire.
Well, I was wondering if they
kept a copy of that warrant
in the Paiute County courthouse.
I would assume so.
I would assume so, too.
May I, uh, may I make a
phone call to the courthouse?
Maybe that'd help me
not resist the, uh...
I'll make the call.
Operator, connect me to the
Paiute County courthouse.
You fight in the war?
You got that look about you.
Probably the right age.
You want to see what I
brought back from Saipan?
I cut the tongue
out of every Jap
I stuck my bayonet through.
He was in Germany.
Tank command.
Killed 40 Krauts in
the Hurtgen forest.
How many was it?
About 40.
You're on the
wrong ranch, peckerwood.
How about I make a
souvenir necklace of my own?
Now, now.
Frank.
You got anything you
wanna say to your son,
you better say it now.
Calm it down, come on.
Calm it down.
I am calm.
Yes, yes, this
is Officer Morton
with the U.S. Marshal Service.
Calling to check on a
status of a warrant,
issue 13 November,
one Benjamin Bonney.
Yes, ma'am.
Yes.
Uh-huh.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Thank you, ma'am.
The warrant's been remanded.
What?
The warrant was
remanded yesterday.
The county clerk's office
forgot to notify the sheriff.
Why weren't we
notified by the field office?
Now here's what's
gonna happen.
Joe Bonney's outside
50 yards away
with a rifle ready to blow a
hole in the side of your head
the second you step
out that front door.
Now I don't want to
filthy up my floor
with a couple of dead marshals,
not any more than it's
already been filthied,
even though I'd be
justified in doing so
'cause you never identified
yourselves as marshals.
You start shooting up
the front of my house.
I have two witnesses for it.
Now, you fly back to
wherever you came from
and don't ever come back here,
and I won't have to
bleach your skulls
and send them home to your
mothers for Christmas.
How's that for
diplomacy, Mormons?
I'll take
that as a yes, sir,
and thank you for not
cutting my nuts off.
Now, if you don't want Joe
to splatter your brains
all over the front yard,
you throw down your guns,
you strip down to
your bare asses,
you take your Walt
Disney Storybook warrant,
and you get the fuck
out of my house!
Call him.
Yes.
I-I don't, I don't understand
how something like
that gets lost
Okay.
Field office confirmed it.
Warrant was remanded yesterday
by somebody higher up.
The sheriff wasn't in the loop.
CO says the evidence
went missing.
That's great news, Frank.
Courthouse building burns
up all the vital records.
Evidence goes magically missing,
and some redneck hillbilly
tyrant takes our
service pistols.
Man, we look like true
professionals, don't we?
I don't like it either--
I can't eve
get a damn light!
Now what was all
that back there, huh?
You shooting up the place
after giving me your little
lecture on procedure?
It was nothing, all right?
Didn't look like nothing.
All right, look,
let's go to a pawn shop,
pick up a couple of pistols.
We'll stay the night in Gilead,
head back in the
morning, close it out.
As far as I'm concerned, this
is the FBI's problem now.
All right.
I'm still pissed they had
clothes that fit you and not me.
Luck of the draw.
Can you at least
give me the belt?
Nope.
Hey.
7AM?
We're not in a
hurry to go anywhere.
Let me sleep in, huh?
Hiya, Tommy.
Well, hello, gorgeous.
What are you wearing?
Take it off.
So this
man, this Zen lunatic,
this Jesus Christ,
this Son of God,
this man who transforms men
and restores him to the land
that once bore him bounty,
this man from the bosom
of the earth brought life,
and it is this life in abundance
that Jesus promises us.
Howdy, Frank.
Transformation makes
the broken world holy,
the skin holy, the nose holy,
the tongue and cock
and asshole holy.
Transformation
makes the soul holy.
Okay, boys.
You go tonight with
the blessings of Jesus.
Have a seat, Frank.
You look spent.
Mind if I smoke my pipe?
Not at all.
I've never seen
a preacher smoke.
Listen, Frank.
If the good Lord didn't
create all manner of plants
on the third day of creation
so we could bunch 'em up into
a piece of hollowed out wood,
and smoke our little hearts out,
I don't know why He
created them at all.
Don't deny yourself for my sake.
I don't smoke.
I quit
after the war.
I just, uh,
needed to do things
a different way.
You know, they used to, uh,
put lithium in this stuff.
Uh-huh.
Why are you here, Frank?
Tonight, here at this hotel?
It's the only
motel in 50 miles.
It was this patch of
concrete or a tent.
You know why I'm here?
Why is that?
I was reading the
book of Genesis,
the first book of the Bible.
I was reading the story
about this man named Jacob,
son of Isaac,
grandson of Abraham.
He spent a great deal
of his life in turmoil.
Gilead was the name of the place
where he laid that turmoil down
and made peace with himself.
That spoke to me.
That's why I'm in Gilead.
I know as a lawman you're
in Gilead because of...
Well, you must be on
some kind of assignment.
But I want to know
why you're here,
in this patch of concrete,
sitting across from me,
when you could be anywhere
else in Gilead, Nevada
you want to be right now.
You want to know why I'm here?
Mm-hmm.
I'll tell you.
It's not because of
some divine path.
There's a man in this
valley killing people.
I'm here to stop him.
Only I can't.
He found a loophole
to keep on doing it,
so I'm packing up
and I'm going home.
It's that simple, Reverend.
There's no neat, tidy
bow to the story.
No happy ending.
No angels and beams of light.
No disrespect, just,
not everything means something.
You got a hunger, Frank,
and a thirst that transcends
your circumstance.
I can see it in the way
you hold your shoulders.
The Lord promises bounty, and
I think you chose this place
because you're here to be fed.
There's no bounty for me here.
It's just another mission.
Captain, we have
to order the men
to pull back to the bridge.
Sir, Murphy's still
pinned down out there.
We can't leave him.
We don't have the fire
power to get this thing down.
We have to pull back.
Order your men to pull back.
He's gonna die.
We're all gonna die.
That thing can't be stopped!
Fall back! Fall back!
Fall back to the bridge!
Sir, we cannot leave him.
He's already dead!
I'm ordering you!
Fall back, now, Captain.
I'm not leaving him to die!
Goddamn it, Captain!
Look around you.
We don't have armor.
We don't have fire support.
We don't have a goddamn bazooka.
This whole thing is fubar!
Now I'm ordering you.
Get your ass over that hill now!
Now, soldier!
Fire!
- Well, hey, there.
- Hey, Callie.
You got a light?
I thought you didn't smoke.
I've been corrupted.
By what?
Circumstance.
Today was a mess.
You found the Bonneys?
I did.
Doesn't matter, not a damn
thing I can do about it.
They're at home safe and sound
and, uh, we're off the case.
We're headed out tomorrow.
Uh, I'll take a
7-UP if you got one cold.
I hate to break it to
you, but I'm all out.
Bar's closing in a
half an hour anyway.
I'll leave you to it.
Ah, there's a vending
machine around the corner.
On me.
Thank you.
You owe me one if
you ever come back.
All right.
Goodnight, Callie.
Tommy!
It's me. It's me.
Call an ambulance.
Call an ambulance!
She's dead.
We got him.
Hey, who sent you, huh?
Who sent you?
Was it the Bonneys?
- Tommy, he's dead.
- Who sent you?
I swear, I'm gonna
blow your head off.
Tommy!
Sheriff says he's a drifter.
There's no way to tie him
to anybody, so that's that.
She's dead, Frank.
Benjamin Bonney put
a hit out on us.
And now some poor
bastard is an orphan.
I'm gonna kill him, Frank.
Hey.
We're off the case.
We're going home.
They got you in room four.
Tommy!
I'm just
trying to find out
who remanded the warrant.
I already told
you, I don't know.
Now stop raising
your voice at me.
I'm not raising
my voice at you.
- I'm just trying to-
- Tommy,
what the hell are you doing?
I'm trying to get
some answers, Frank.
Who remanded it?
Was it the sheriff?
Get out!
Tommy, Tommy, listen to me.
You're not gonna get
anywhere by scaring-
No, you know what I'm
not gonna do, Frank?
I'm not gonna stand around
with a thumb up my ass
while Benjamin
Bonney goes around
murdering hundreds of people.
Now where did you
put the warrant?
Is it in the records office?
Because it doesn't look
like that burned down.
Get out of the courthouse.
I have jurisdiction!
I will deal with him.
- Tommy.
- What?
You're not thinking straight.
I've been thinking
straight all night.
Yeah.
We got sent here with a
warrant issued by this county.
Benjamin Bonney
is killing people
and somehow somebody
in this county
lost the only piece of evidence
tying the Bonneys
to the murders.
And then, like magic, that
warrant is suddenly pulled.
Now who do you think
pulled it, Frank?
John F. Kennedy, huh?
Somebody in this goddamn
shithole town is crooked.
Yes, they are.
Hey, they're crooked,
- all right?
- Yeah.
So what?
So somebody fucking
died last night, Frank!
Okay, flyboy, what are
you gonna do about it?
Do you think whoever
remanded that warrant
signed their name at the bottom,
filed it in permanent records?
We are done.
We are going home.
Accept it.
Maybe, I think maybe
there's a chance.
And maybe it's worth
looking at the land records
from that year just
because everything else
went up in ashes, Frank.
And I think maybe you
might actually give a shit
if your balls weren't
permanently locked up
in a cabinet since 1945.
Drop the folders.
Drop them right now and
let me see your hands.
Daniel?
What the hell are you doing?
Man, I almost shot you.
Goddamn, brother.
Never thought I'd
run into you again.
Not in the middle of the
desert, that's for sure.
What has
it been, 10 years?
More that that I
think, what, '51, right?
Hey, you should have
seen this flyboy.
He was driving
fighters in Korea.
Best wingman I ever had.
When I wasn't saving your ass.
Oh, no, no, no, uh-uh.
You were saving my ass?
I don't think so.
I know a couple of MiG
pilots in parachutes,
they'd swear to it.
We're gonna do this again?
You know I had that shot.
I know you think
you had that shot.
After I saved his ass, we
both got out, went to college.
He went Marshals, I went FBI.
What are the chances?
So you're FBI.
Yeah, they got us down
on field assignment.
Who's us?
I'm not really
at liberty to say.
You know how that goes.
Does the
name Benjamin Bonney
mean anything to you?
Whoa.
No, no, I'm just saying-
- Come on, man.
- we were sent here
with a warrant for his arrest
and we get here and suddenly
somebody makes the warrant
just disappear.
Tommy, you listen to me.
I got a little office here.
I'm doing my job, I like my job.
Okay?
You can't just come in and
pump me for information.
It don't work like that.
That's not what I'm doing.
I just need a little
something, man.
Tell me-
Are you on active assignment?
That's an excellent question.
Mr. Armstrong, they're
U.S. Marshals, sir.
They check out.
That doesn't
answer my question.
Are you on
an active assignment?
No, sir.
We are following up
on a recent case.
What kind of case?
We were called in
by the county
to serve a
murder warrant.
Evidence got lost,
so my partner and I were
doing a little follow up.
Murder warrant?
Killing over land.
The old ways never
change, do they?
Yeah, they do,
if you change them.
Tommy and I, we flew missions
together in Korea, sir.
He's a good pilot,
a very good man.
Investigations are
FBI jurisdiction.
As you no longer have
active warrants to serve,
you'll need to return
to your station.
Carson City.
That's a 15 hour drive.
Call the air station
at, uh, White Rock
and charter these
gentlemen a flight
tomorrow morning, first thing.
You can, uh, leave the
car at the airport.
We'll take care of it.
Professional courtesy.
That is mighty
kind of you, sir.
We will get out of your hair.
Daniel.
Take
care of yourself.
Excuse me, sir.
I spent an entire year
taking Chinese flak,
trying to save South Korea
from that madman Kim.
It was black and white.
You got the good guys over here
and the bad guys over there.
You suit up, you go shoot
rockets at the bad guy.
And now the good guys are
shooting rockets at us.
I think
I liked it better
when they were communists.
At least it made sense.
It doesn't make sense.
It doesn't have to.
7AM?
7AM.
Hey,
Captain.
Something ain't right.
See it?
Yeah, I see it.
Some
kind of signals?
Krauts must be dug in.
It means there's more
of them out there.
I don't have a good
feeling about this.
Hey, maybe we ought
to let this one go.
We back off, we go
around these pricks.
Cut 'em off at their supply.
They'll surrender to the first
unit that comes across 'em.
Sergeant, every drop of blood
those Krauts spill
from here on out,
that's on your hands and mine.
So, if you're not willing
to live with that,
get your rifle
pointed down range.
Let's take out some bad guys.
Starting to think you got
a thing for being corrupted.
Drinking your problems away?
The intrepid U.S. Marshal.
Badge and gun in his motel room,
indulges in spirits and barmaids
just to ease the
pain that he exists.
What are you doing
here, Benjamin?
What am I doing here?
I'll have what he's having.
Make it two.
I spent my day on top of
my roof plugging holes
so that when it
snows next month,
it doesn't, it doesn't
drain down into the house
and onto the holes on the
floor that I just patched.
It's November.
It's damn hot and I
worked up a sweat,
so I reckon I,
thank you,
deserve a respite
for my troubles.
What do you say?
You put that on his tab.
He owes me one.
You here to shoot
up my room again?
Someone shot up your room?
You got a lot of nerve.
I would love nothing more
than to blow your insides
out all over this bar.
Can't think of a
good reason yet.
Go on, drink it.
Drink it.
Now...
I'm gonna tell you a story,
Marshal, about my mother dying.
Bartender, two more.
Doubles.
She was killed on her own ranch,
the one you just shot up,
during an insurrection
of the Paiute Indians
and the federal government.
Was shot in the stomach.
My father held
her while she died
while I sat there
inside watching.
She was killed by
a 10-year-old boy.
Go on now.
I knew that boy.
His name was Tu-cu-pit.
That's Paiute speak
for a mountain lion.
He shot her in the stomach.
She died right there on
the ranch you just shot up.
My father held
her while she died
and I stood inside watching.
Pour two more.
Eventually, the federals
crushed the uprising
and killed all the
leaders and it was over.
And Tu-cu-pit was still alive
and he went back to his
boarding school the next week
like nothing happened.
You know what I did?
What?
I found his boarding school
and I watched him from
the woods for a month,
watching him learn
how to plant corn.
Then one day, he was alone,
so I took a rock, hit him
in the back of the head.
And I kept on hitting him
until his skull cracked.
Then I dragged his
body into a ditch
and then I pulled
out my jackknife
and in the rage of a child,
I did what a child would do.
I cut off his head.
That's, add two more.
Come on now.
You know how I felt?
- How did-
- Not the slightest
bit guilty.
Slept like a baby.
From that day on,
I never lost a minute of
sleep for killing that boy.
Drink.
Anyone who survived
the insurrection,
they knew Tu-cu-pit
had killed my mother,
so they assumed my father
cut his head off in revenge.
So the next day,
they shot my father
right in his own front yard.
Naturally, they
cut his head off.
No more mother.
No more father.
No more 10,000 acres
I lost to the bank.
All for making sure that
that kid got his comeuppance.
Now, as a U.S. Marshal,
I'm sure that you
feel really inspired
to follow every injustice
down to the end of a rope.
The point I'm
trying to make here,
that sometimes you need to know
when to go back to your
fucking house and stay there.
Those are for you, honey.
I don't drink.
Four bucks.
And you still owe me a drink.
You all right?
There's a time I had the fire
to do something about that.
I don't know if I need to
feed that fire or put it out.
Might be best to not ever
light it to begin with.
World's got enough fires.
Fire by an outlaw's hand
or being vaporized
in a nuclear inferno.
Either way, the whole
world's consumed by it.
Everybody burns.
Got a light?
Frank?
Frank, is that you?
It's Danny, open up.
It's unlocked.
We need to talk.
Come on in.
You're hungry.
You're smoking
cigarettes and drinking
after years of sobriety,
'cause you're hungry
for something.
Well, once in a while
a guy's gotta cut loose.
You knocked on my door
because you have an urgency,
a burning desire deep
inside you, Frank,
to break out of
your constraints.
You know how Jacob
came to Gilead?
Jacob who?
Jacob from the Bible.
Yeah, right.
Uh...
No, I don't know how Jacob
came to be in Gilead.
Because he was traveling
to reconcile his burdens.
And the Lord chose Gilead
as the place of reconciliation.
Good to know.
In Gilead, he was transformed.
Have you ever embarked on
a psychedelic trip before?
No.
I think you're long overdue.
Smoke it.
What's the jig, Daniel?
No jig, just deep shit.
- Deep shit, huh?
- Yeah.
Okay, so you're here to what?
Scare me away again?
Tommy, you remember
the Pusan run?
January of '51, K9 airbase.
- Yeah.
- Couple of MIG-15s?
Yeah, I remember
the Pusan run.
You remember what happened?
We lost Joker.
Joker wasn't supposed
to fly that day.
He felt a sense of duty.
Leapfrogged the roster,
flew himself in front
of a MiG ace's cannon,
and that was the end.
All the honor, all the
glory, 21 gun salute
and wings punching the top
of his coffin, still dead.
That's you right now.
You're Joker.
Stay on the base, Tommy.
Sit this one out.
I'm not built for hanging
back at base, Danny.
I'll take my chances
getting shot.
I gotta see this through.
I tried.
My boss made that
shell casing disappear.
Galen Armstrong, he got
rid of the only evidence.
The only evidence tying
the Bonneys to the murders.
He's the one that
torched the archives
and remanded the warrant.
I don't know why.
He's got something
cooking and it's bad.
The Bonneys are killing people.
Armstrong's letting it happen.
Whose side are you on, Daniel?
Fair winds and
following seas, brother.
Transformations are spiritual.
Jacob's transformation
was spiritual,
but it was a physical encounter.
He woke up in the
middle of the night,
sleeping by the road to Gilead,
and found himself
wrestling with an angel.
The angel took
the form of a man,
and there Jacob
wrestled with that man
till the breaking of the day.
Let me go.
And when the man saw that
Jacob prevailed against him,
he touched the
hollow of his thigh.
No.
And the hollow of Jacob's
thigh was out of joint
as he wrestled with him.
And that man said, "Let me go!"
The day breaketh,
and he says, "I
will not let thee go
until thou bless me."
And the angel blessed him there.
Your struggle, Frank.
You're wrestling with an angel.
You're wrestling with yourself.
You ready to do this?
Let's shoot 'em out
the goddamn window, sir.
Be prepared to cover me
if we start taking
fire from the woods.
Ready?
Go!
Till the fucking
house is falling!
"Death be not proud."
Let's go kill them
fucking Nazis.
"Though some call thee
mighty and dreadful,
thou are not so.
Those whom thou thinkest
thou dost overthrow die not!
Poor death nor yet
canst thou kill me
from rest and sleep.
Rest!
Their bones and soul's delivery!
Poppy or charms make
us sleep as well.
And better than thy stroke!
Why swellest thou then?
One short sleep past,
we wake eternally.
And death shall be no more."
"Death shall die."
Jacob called the place of
his struggle, He Who Strives.
For I have seen
God face to face,
and my life is preserved.
For Jacob was righteous
in the eyes of the Lord.
We're shooting rockets
at the North Koreans.
What are you
talking about, Frank?
You said you liked
shooting at the bad guys.
We know where the bad guys are.
Let's shoot at them.
What are you on, Frank?
Remember this?
That's every land
deed and bill of sale
in Paiute County this year.
Every one of them deeded
to Benjamin Bonney
for pennies on the dollar.
He's murdering to create a panic
and buying out everyone
within 20 miles of his ranch.
This is all
circumstantial evidence.
But lucky for us,
that's no longer our problem.
Pack your rockets, Tommy.
There's a war on.
The Bonneys have been
in that barn for an hour.
They're not coming out.
Then we're going in.
You got the duffel, right?
Yeah.
You sure that's how
you want to play this?
I've never been more sure
of anything in my life.
We're gonna get Bonney,
we're gonna take down Armstrong,
or we're gonna wind
up dead or in prison.
That all right with you?
Better to die a hero
than live as a coward.
That's the spirit.
Let's get 'em, cowboy.
Don't move!
U.S. Marshals,
you're under arrest.
Don't do it.
Don't.
Tommy, you need to see this.
Holy shit.
was
shot just below the shoulder,
according to
who spoke with the
governor at the hospital
where he.
asked where
the shooter came from,
and the Governor
replied, "I don't know.
I guess from the back."
Benjamin Bonney.
You are under arrest
for capital murder.
Do not make any sudden
moves, either of you.
What the hell is this?
Yeah, how'd you get in here?
Where are my sons?
Noah and Ahab are dead.
That's right.
You tell us where Joe is,
and maybe he survives.
You can't make an
arrest without a warrant.
See, a little birdie showed
up on our doorstep last night
with your missing evidence.
That's probable cause.
Gentlemen,
this is our insurance policy.
You're gonna answer some
questions on the record.
Mr. Armstrong, I'm aware
that you can make a
shell casing disappear.
But this recording is getting
air-mailed to Washington.
And you will not
make that disappear.
So why don't we start
with where the hell we are?
Why's there a rocket down here?
The President
of the United States,
John Fitzgerald Kennedy,
has been confirmed dead at
Dallas Parkland Hospital
at 1 o'clock p.m.
local time today.
Lyndon Baines Johnson
- has currently assumed the-
- Is that real?
the oath of
office and will be sworn in-
President
John F. Kennedy
who was shot by a
would-be assassin-
You telling me
that the President of the
United States is dead?
And you had something
to do with it?
What's going on?
It's a new world
and the end of yours.
Stay where you are.
Don't move, I've
got you in my sights!
That would be my daughter,
Jo.
What the hell
are you doing here?
Drop your guns, both of you.
You shoot and Daddy here dies!
Frank, I've got your
partner in my sights.
Tell him to drop his gun.
You got no choice,
drop your guns.
Not gonna happen.
What the hell are you doing?
Why are you here?
Drop your guns!
I'm gonna blow his brains out!
Hey!
Hey, you want a confession?
I'll give you a confession.
We're standing in
a missile silo.
What you saw in the other room
is a rocket with an atom bomb
strapped to the top of it.
Those Soviet engineers
from Angola or whatever
have been down here building
it for what purposes,
I don't know and I-I don't care.
If you want to
know, you ask him.
I personally don't give
one single solitary fuck
about the Soviets
or the missiles.
Me?
I just like a good deal.
And that's what Mr.
Armstrong proposed to me.
Yeah, he wanted his privacy.
He didn't want neighbors
snooping around.
I heard that.
Made a deal.
What I do is keep
the locals away
by any means at my
disposal.
Yeah, and he makes sure
the scrutiny goes away.
You let him murder
with impunity?
For land?
Yeah, you're goddamn
right, Marshals.
I'm killing for land, yeah.
I want that land.
That's my land.
It's always been my land.
That land will be mine
for a thousand years.
That will be my land without
any consequences at all.
I own you, I own your badges,
I own your family,
I own your asses.
Put down your guns,
get on your knees,
and pray to whatever
God you can think of
that we don't slash you from
your asshole to your elbows
and leave your guts
bleaching in the sun.
That's your only chance,
you cherry fucks.
You better take it.
You killed the president?
You're goddamn right we did.
So what power do
you think you have?
Get him!
Dr. Hansi, we have a code nine.
You know what to do.
I don't speak Russian.
Who are you?
Are you with Mr. Armstrong?
No, I'm not.
What is this?
This is your day of reckoning.
What kind of reckoning?
You are in a missile silo.
Why don't you do the math?
You're launching it?
At what?
Tell me.
Hey!
I've got your scientist.
What is this, Armstrong?
You launching a missile?
Marshal...
I'm, uh...
I'm going to explain
something to you.
Imagine you have a,
a Russian soldier
with a gun pointing
at your head.
Now, if he fires, you die
before you can get
off a shot in defense.
But he's not going to fire
because you have 1,000
American soldiers
standing behind you
pointing guns at him.
If he shoots, you
die, but so does he.
It's mutually
assured destruction.
If I turn that key,
the nuclear missile
in the next room
will launch into the
city of Los Angeles.
You can't stop it.
But if you put down your gun,
you have a historic,
once-in-a-lifetime opportunity
to convince me to
change my mind.
Why should I believe you?
You could
gamble with the lives
of every man, woman, and
child in Los Angeles,
if you prefer.
All right, Frank.
Save Los Angeles.
Tell me to fire the
missile somewhere else.
Say it.
Fire the missile
somewhere else.
Okay.
What are you doing?
I am reprogramming the missile
to land on the
bustling metropolis
of Cactus City, California,
population zero.
It's a ghost town.
This is not part of the plan.
The plans were to wait
successful news about the-
Of the killing of
President Kennedy,
and then launch the
missile at Los Angeles.
We're changing the plan.
We're saving the world.
You cannot change the plan.
You cannot!
We just did, Dr. Hansi.
I just saved America
from a Russian plot
to destroy Los Angeles from
one of America's own silos.
I'm a hero.
You killed the president.
I killed the rot that's
plagued this country
since Stalin
marched into Berlin.
When that missile
lands in the desert,
the whole world will think
Russia killed the president,
and launched an atomic
bomb at Los Angeles
and missed by the grace of God.
Flattening a ghost
town's not enough
to justify wiping Russia off
the map with our own arsenal,
but it stops every
politician in this country
from coddling the
Reds once and for all.
I just made every wobbly-kneed,
fence-sitting senator
and fifth-column voters' league
opposing the defense
of this country
just as much a danger
as Moscow itself.
Hell, I just got every
nation in the West
to stand up and commit
to stopping the, the
spread of communism
to Chile and Vietnam.
I'm a patriot, Frank.
What are you?
It's not
too late to stop this.
I'm sorry about your father,
but it's not too late.
My father's death
served a greater cause.
It's like I told you.
If you're preparing for
war, you've already lost it.
You cannot do this!
You made a deal with
Moscow, you treasonous scum!
You're going to burn
in hell for this!
Do you hear me?
You're going to burn!
Jo.
Do you know the protocol?
I know the protocol.
Prepare the launch sequence.
I want this thing in
the air in 10 minutes.
Get our man of
Mexico on the line.
See if he's got full
confirmation on Kennedy.
Looked pretty dead to me.
Any chance they
can survive this?
It's gonna be 6,000 degrees
when this thing goes up.
Won't be so much as a
pile of ashes left over.
Come on, let's get
'er in the air.
"And now, I am become death.
Destroyer of worlds."
So this is it, huh?
We're cooked?
More or less.
But that doesn't mean
we can't stop them.
Stop them how?
You're saying we could, we
can turn this thing off?
Quite easily.
There is no permissive
action link on the warhead.
I can run up there
with a screwdriver
and pull a few wires.
But I am not going to do that.
What do you mean
you're not gonna do that?
Why?
Because it is
now my sworn duty
to give them a taste
of their own medicine.
Only a fool would
trust that man.
And I am not a fool!
So I built an electronic
release on a fuel valve.
And now, it's armed.
We flip this switch and rocket
fuel starts bleeding out.
Slow enough they won't notice.
10 minutes later,
the charge goes off
next to the oxider seal,
the gas mixes, and 150
tons of rocket fuel
goes off in half a second.
And that is the end.
No.
Disarm it!
You crawl up there
and you disarm it!
We can live to
fight another day.
If you know how to reprogram
a D-17 main frame computer
and fly this missile
into the ocean,
then we live to
fight another day.
But that won't stop Mr.
Armstrong and those maniacs.
It will only slow them down.
So it's his plan or mine.
Choose!
Kennedy's dead.
Then, uh, you'll
need the launch code.
Your plan will kill them.
Right?
We are talking about
150 tons of rocket fuel.
That is enough to put a blast
door into solid granite.
Do it.
It's a go.
It is a nice day to
die for your country.
How long we got?
Five minutes.
Where's Tommy?
He gave 'em hell.
Let's go. Let's go.
Farewell, old friend.
To a better world.
Oh, my.
Are you the chaplain?
Do you see what I've done?
Redemption is a
long road, Frank.
This is your road to Gilead.
What do I do now?
Vavavoom.
Drive it, baby.